字幕：Hongjiang399  微信：Hongjiang399
当你从甲骨文网站下载和安装Java时，你其实是
When you download and install Java from Oracle you are installing a number
安装一系列开发工具
of development tools.
安装包叫做Java SE开发工具(JDK)，其包含
The package is called the Java SE Development Kit or JDK and it includes the
执行器，编译器以及其他工具
runtime, a compiler, and many other tools.
第一个你将用到的是编译器
The first tool you'll be using is the compiler.
这是一个叫javac的程序
It's an application called javac.
这个程序的名字是统一的，不管你
And the name of the application will be the same, regardless of whether you are
用的是Mac、Windows、Linux或者其他操作系统
working on Mac, Windows, Linux or any other operating system.
当你运行javac时，你需提供你的源码文件名称，然后
When you run javac you are provided with the names of your source code files and
javac将会输出一些字节码文件
the resulting output will be a set of bytecode files.
当运行一程序时你需要运用“java”命令
To run an application you use the command java.
这命令对于任何操作系统也是统一的
Again it looks the same on any operating system.
当你运行java命令，你需提供一个类的名称
When you run the java command, you'll provide it with the name of the class that
该类包含程序的开头
you want to start with.
我随后将会展示一些例子
I'll show you an example of that in a few moments.
JDK也包含了另一些工具
The JDK also includes many other tools.
"jar"工具让你可以打包你编写的程序
The jar tool lets you package up your applications.
一个完整的Java程序通常包含很多类，当你
A complete Java application will typically consist of many classes, and when you
编译这些类时，你会得到一大堆独立文件
compile the classes, you end up with a whole bunch of files.
但如果打包成一个文件，那在发布程序时将很方便，
But it's a lot more convenient to deliver the application as a single file, and
这时你可以用jar程序来实现打包
so you use the jar application to do that packaging.
当你打包文件时，会得到一个zip格式的压缩文件
When you package up the files you end up with an archive file in zip format, but
文件的扩展名为".jar"
with the file extension of .jar.
javadoc程序可以根据你在代码中的注释创建文档
The javadoc application lets you create documentation based on comments in your source code.
我将会在以后的视频中介绍
I'll show you how to use this in a later video in the series.
还有很多其他命令也是包含在JDK当中的
And there are many other command line tools that are a part of the JDK.
那么，你该如何开始？
So how do you get started?
Java程序是从包含源代码的纯文本文件来构建的
Well your Java applications are built in source code files that are pure text files.
你可以用任何文本编辑器来创建代码，尽管如此，本课程中
You can create these text files in any Text Editor, although, I'll be using the
我将会利用Eclipse集成环境来写代码
Eclipse Integrated Development Environment throughout this course.
下面是一个典型的Hello World程序
Here is a classic Hello World application.
如果你用过其他语言，你可能会习惯于
If you've worked in other programming languages, you might be accustomed to
用仅一行代码来实现Hello World程序
Hello World applications being just a single line of code.
但Java并不是这样
That's not the case in Java.
Java中所有东西都是封装在某个类中的，包括
In Java everything is encapsulated in a class of some kind, including
你程序的开始代码
your start-up code.
因此屏幕展示的这些代码应该是
So this bit of code that I have on the screen represents the simplest
最为简单的Java程序
possible Java application.
第一行代码叫包的声明
The first line of code is called the package declaration.
它表明了在你的工程中这个源码文件所处的位置
It indicates the location of the source code file within your project.
包声明通常是一个点分隔字符串，包的开头
The package declaration is typically a dot separated string, the beginning of
一般是你的域名的逆序，因此lynda.com
the package frequently is your domain name in reverse order, so lynda.com
这里变成com.lynda
might become com.lynda.
包名剩下的部分一般表明程序的类型，可以是
And then the rest of the package indicates what type of application it might be
你所在的组织
within your organization.
下一行代码叫做类声明
The next line of code is called the class declaration.
如果你创建一个名为HelloWorld.java文件，其包含一个公共类
If you create a file called HelloWorld. java it can contain one public class and
那么类名必须要跟文件名一致，因此HelloWorld.java文件
the name of the class must match the name of the file, so the HelloWorld.java
必须包含一个名为HelloWorld的公共类，注意名字一致
file contains a public class named HelloWorld and notice they match exactly.
Java是对大小写敏感的，所以你必须确保所有字符严格一致
Java is a case-sensitive language and you must match these strings precisely.
在类里面，有一个叫main的方法
Within the class there is something called a main method.
当你在命令行运行Java程序，Java会寻找
When you run a Java application from the command line Java will look for this
这个特定的方法并自动执行
particular method and execute it automatically.
这个方法的名称必须是"main"(小写)
The name of the method or function must be main lower case.
这个函数的前面三个关键字为public、static以及
And the three keywords previous to the function name public, static, and
void，都是必须的
void are also required.
我会在后面解释它们
I'll explain what they mean later on.
main方方法必须接收一个参数，且必须为
The main method must receive something called an argument and it must be
一个字符串数组
an array of strings.
这让你可以给程序传输一条信息，特别是你从命令行运行程序时
This allows you to pass an information to the application as you run it from the command line.
我们把参数叫做args
We call that the args argument.
最后，在main方法里，你写上需执行的代码
Finally within the main method, you place your executable code.
这个程序就是简单地把Hello World文字输出到命令行上
This application simply outputs the text Hello World to the command line using
使用了“System.out.println”命令
the command System.out.println or print line.
注意这句话的结尾有一分号
Notice that this string is ended with a semicolon.
分号就如英语中的句号，表示一个程序语句的结束
The semicolon is like a period in English, it means this is the end of the statement.
因此“System.out.println("Hello World")”表示输出“Hello World”到命令行中
So System.out.println("Hello World") means output the string Hello World to the command line.
现你创建了源码文件，并且放置到你工程文件夹的某处
So you create that source code file and you place it somewhere in your project folder.
在这例子中我声明了软件包名称为"com.lynda.javatraining;"
Now in this case I have declared a package named com.lynda.javatraining;
表明我放置源代码文件到相应路径所代表
and so I have to place the source code file in an equivalent
的子文件夹中
subfolder structure.
如果HelloWorld是我的工程文件夹名称，那么"com\lynda\javatraining"是
If HelloWorld is the name of my project folder, then com\lynda\javatraining is
我的软件包文件夹，这与源码中的软件包点分隔声明是相对应的
my package folder, matching the dot separated package as declared in the source code.
源代码文件的名称之前我说过是"HelloWorld.java"
The name of the file as I have indicated before is HelloWorld.java.
".java"扩展是你的所有源码文件所必须的
The .java extension is required in all of your source code files.
为编译这个文件，我从工程文件夹HelloWorld开始
To actually compile that file, I would start at the project directory
我运行javac命令，并指向Java的源码文件
HelloWorld, I would execute the javac command and I'd reference the Java source
HelloWorld
code file HelloWorld.
注意我在源码文件名前加上了斜杠分隔
Notice that I am prefixing the name of the file with a slash separated syntax,
"com\lynda\javatraining"然后是文件名
com\lynda\javatraining\ and then the name of the file.
这个视频录制的是Windows系统，所以我用反斜杠，如果你
This screenshot comes from Windows, so I am using backslashes, but if you were
用Mac系统，你应该用正斜杠
working on Mac you would use forward slashes.
编译完后你会发现一新文件，原本的源码文件是
After compilation you end up with a new file, the original source code file was
"HelloWorld.java"，编译出来的文件是"HelloWorld.class"
HelloWorld.java, the resulting compiled file is HelloWorld.class.
".class"文件是你的字节码文件，由于这个程序
The .class file is your bytecode file, and because this is an application that
只包含了一个类，所以这个.class文件已包含整个程序
only has the single class, that .class file comprises your entire application.
因此实际上你在发布应用时，你不需要发布
So in fact when you are delivering the application you don't have to deliver the
.java文件，你只需要发布.class文件
.java file, you only deliver the classes.
为了运行这个程序，我要用到java命令
Now to run the application from the command line I would use the java command.
我会再次从工程文件夹HelloWorld开始，然后调用
I would once again start in the project directory HelloWorld and I'd call the
class文件的点分隔路径，就像在源码中的软件包声明语句
class using dot separated syntax, just like the package was declared in the
一样："com.lynda.javatraining.HelloWorld"
source code, com.lynda.javatraining.HelloWorld.
注意当我运行程序时我并未引用
And notice that when I run the application I am not referencing the file
文件扩展名".class"，我只是引用了文件名："HelloWorld"
extension .class, I am only referencing the class name, HelloWorld.
程序被执行且结果被输出到终端上
The application runs and the resulting output appears in the console.
上面介绍了基本Java语法以及如何编译、运行一个
So that's a look at basic Java syntax and how you would compile and run a very
简单的命令行程序
simple application from the command line.
在剩下的课程中，我会介绍如何利用
Now throughout the rest of the course, I'll be showing you how to do this in the
集成开发环境Eclipse编写程序
Integrated Development Environment called Eclipse.
大多数情况下你不需要接触到命令行下的编译和运行
And for the most part you'll be protected from compiling and running directly
但对此的了解还是十分重要，特别是你想
from the command line, but it's important to know that if you want to work in
用命令行你就能用这方法
this way you certainly can.
一旦你学会了用Java语言，你可以用在什么地方？
So once you've learned how to work in Java, where can you use it?
Java能在多种环境下实现，并用于多种不同
Well Java is implemented in many environments and used for many different
的应用程序
kinds of applications.
你可以用Java开发桌面程序，或通过直接安装到
You can use Java for Desktop applications either actually installed on the
桌面系统中，或通过把Java嵌入到HTML网页中用浏览器运行
Desktop or delivered through browsers as Java applets embedded in HTML pages.
这些叫做图形化Java程序，它们用了一些库例如Swing
These are called Graphical Java applications and they use libraries called Swing
和AWT来构建可视化的界面
and AWT to build their visual presentation.
你也能用Java开发动态网页应用，也就是
You can also use Java to build dynamic Web applications, that is, applications
通过HTML加载到浏览器上的应用，在服务器上运行时会被动态生成
that are delivered to the browser as HTML, dynamically generated at runtime on a server.
这些应用有时叫做J2EE，亦称Java企业版本
These are sometimes called J2EE or simply Java Enterprise Edition
应用，它们一般是在服务器环境中运行，例如Tomcat等环境
applications and they are executed within server environments such as Tomcat
来自Apache或者JBoss
from Apache or JBoss.
这些代码是基于一些模型编写的，模型被称为servlets或者JavaServerPages
The code is written using models called servlets and JavaServer Pages.
这跟编写桌面应用的是同一门语言，但只是
It's exactly the same language as you might use on the Desktop but it's simply
在模型上有点不一样
modeled a little bit differently.
近年来对Java最为流行的应用是移动设备上
And one of the most popular recent uses of Java is on mobile devices.
谷歌的安卓平台利用他们自己名为Dalvik的编译器以及
The Google Android environment uses its own compiler called Dalvik and tools
能在Eclipse运行的谷歌的工具，来创建应用
provided by Google that run in Eclipse to build applications that run on
运行于安卓手机和平板上
Android phones and tablets.
黑莓操作系统同样用Java语言，因此你可以用Java来
The BlackBerry Operating System also uses Java, so you can use Java to write
编写程序运行于黑莓手机上，另外你还能把Java
applications that run on BlackBerry phones, and you can use Java in many other
用在其他很多移动平台
mobile environments as well.
实际上你能用Java开发所有类型的应用，如游戏、移动应用
You can in fact use Java to build all sorts of applications, games, mobile apps,
云计算应用、分布式系统、数据库、网页嵌入系统
cloud computing applications, distributed systems, databases, websites embedded
图像管理、企业信息化管理、等等
systems, image management, enterprise information management, and many more.
至今，你已经大致了解Java的历史、
So now that you've had a sense of how Java is architected its history, its
语法、规则以及怎么样编译和运行Java程序，是时候
principles, its syntax and how you compile and run Java applications, it's time
开始安装Java并编写代码了
to get started with installing Java and writing your own code.
字幕GitHub: https://github.com/Hongjiang399/JavaEssentialTrainingSRT.git